Minh Tran

Herndon, Virginia, United States



linkedin.com/in/minh-tran-aba04a127



tranminh631@gmail.com



7036749000

Summary

Software Developer in Test with over three years of experience. Web development skills include Cypress, Selenium, Node, and React. Highest traffic site ever worked on was Special Olympics 2017 website, which got over 1 million hits in an hour.

Experience

FINITAL Developer

FINRA

Jun 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Collaborated with a cross functional team of designers, business analysts, developers, and testers to create a product with high user experience for both internal and external users.

Automated front-end testing using Java Selenium and Cucumber. Used both xpath and CSS selectors to validate website functionality in accordance with design documentation.

Ensured the REST APIs returned the correct responses across all test cases with Jackson and REST Assured. Validated the role based privileges for all possible use cases using an Access Control Matrix.

Confirmed the validity of GraphQL APIs via automated generation of test cases for use with Junit5.

Operated in an Agile Scrum environment. Participated in sprint planning, standups, grooming, and retrospectives.

>

Software Developer In Test

ettain group

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018 (1 year)

Collaborated with business analysts and developers to ensure the validity of ETL jobs in the AWS/Spark ecosystem. Confirmed daily ETL jobs in accordance with federal options and fixed income securities rules.

Mirrored the developer's ETL based on requirement documentation through Spark and Scala in order to ensure quality of the ETL.

Confirmed the database validity of migration from on-premise to AWS S3. Automated comparison of all database files using Java, AWS SDK, and FINRA internal data management system. Checked file size, contents, S3 location, and data management fields.

Generated Apache Hive scripts for small one-off changes.

Operated in an Agile Scrum environment. Participated in sprint planning, standups, grooming, and retrospectives.

PS Development Intern

Perfect Sense

May 2016 - Aug 2016 (4 months)

Produced an internal Marriott website with a small team of development interns.

Collaborated with designer and QA department in order to validate design and functionality.

Developed front-end in accordance with design documentation in HTML5, CSS/LESS, jQuery, and Handlebars.js.

PS Development Intern

Perfect Sense

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (3 months)

Finished development on specialolympics.org for summer 2015 games. Supported launch of website which received over 1 million hits in under 24 hours.

Performed back-end development using Java and Brightspot CMS framework.

Education

📕 Virginia Tech

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science

2012 - 2016

Graduated in December from Virginia Tech with a Bachelors in Computer Science and a Minor in Business.

Focused education on Human Computer Interaction in Computer Science for the creation of front-ends with high user experience..

Developed capstone project for Oculus VR. Facilitated viewing of local creek in a virtual reality environment using panoramic images.

Licenses & Certifications

ISTQB Certified Tester - ASTQB - ISTQB in the U.S. - Official Page 18-CTFL-02026-USA

Skills

Java • JavaScript • HTML5 • Web Development • Scala • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • jQuery • LESS • MySQL • JSON